Thomas Lowe Hughes Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Department of State, 1947-2009 (Box 15-36)
  - Bureau of Intelligence and Research (INR) (Box 15)
    - Hilsman, Roger, press, 1964 (Box 23)
    - Index to Department of State files, 1961-1970 (Box 23)
    - Inspectors, briefings, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
    - Invitations, 1964 (Box 23)
    - Invitations and ephemera, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
    - Invitations, list to meet President Nixon, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 1964 See also Container CL 2, same heading (Box 23)
    - Khrushchev's letters project, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
    - Kirkpatrick, Jeane (consultant), 1964 (Box 23)
    - Kunkel, John C., conversation, "Tape for Broadcast," 1964 (Box 23)
    - Lall, Betty, Soviet Union notes, 1966 (Box 23)
    - Leaving INR, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Luncheon for Commonwealth ambassadors, 1965 (Box 23)
    - Marder, Murray, research on American-Soviet misperceptions, 1963-1964, 1977-1983 (Box 23)
    - Memoranda, INR, 1961-1966 See also Container CL 2, same heading (Box 23)
    - Memoranda to secretary of state, 1961-1968 (Box 23)
    - Miscellany, 1960-1969, undated, (7 folders) (Box 24)
    - "Musings by Hughes," 1961-1963 (Box 24)
    - New York state scholarship committee, 1966-1968 (Box 24)
    - Nixon administration, 1969 (Box 24)
    - Notes (Box 24)
      - Assistant secretary's meeting, 1961-1965 See also Container CL 2, same heading, (4 folders) (Box 24)
      - Congress, views from the Department of State, 1960s (Box 24)
      - "Important," 1964-1997 (Box 24)
      - Latin American political climate, 1963 See also Container CL 2, same heading (Box 24)
      - Miscellaneous, 1961-1963 See also Container CL 2, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 24)
      - Miscellaneous, 1963-1969 See also Container CL 2, same heading, (3 folders) (Box 25)
      - Presidency, John F. Kennedy, command and control, 1961-1964 (Box 25)
      - "S" and "U" staff meetings, 1968-1969 See also Container CL 2, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Secretary's policy planning meeting, 1963-1965 See also Container CL 2, same heading, (3 folders) (Box 25)
      - Secretary's staff meeting, 1963-1967, (6 folders) (Box 25)
      - "U" staff meetings, 1967 (Box 25)
      - Undersecretary's staff meeting, 1965 (Box 25)
      - Vietnam, 1964-1965, 1995-1998 (Box 26)
    - Parties, 1961-1969 See also Container CL 2, same heading (Box 26)
    - Parties, personal and INR, 1963-1971 See also Container CL 2, same heading (Box 26)
    - Passports and badge, 1947-1981 (Box 26)
    - Peace Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 26)
    - Political project (to read for secretary), 1964 (Box 26)
    - Procedures for Department of State review of government-sponsored research, 1965 (Box 26)
    - "Profiles of Newly Independent States," Geographic Bulletin No. 1, 1967 (Box 26)
    - Project Camelot, 1965 (Box 26)
    - Protocol, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Research file, intelligence (C.I.A., etc.), 1967-1968 (Box 26)
    - Research, President Johnson, 1963 (Box 26)
    - Resignation, correspondence with William P. Rogers, 1969-1971 (Box 27)
    - Retrospective notes on INR, 1997-2009, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Rusk, Dean (Box 27)
      - General, 1963-1964, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - On communism, 1967 (Box 27)
    - Satellites, 1961-1962 (Box 27)
    - Senate testimony, 1966-1968, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Significant foreign developments, 1963-1967 (Box 27)
    - Sorenson, Theodore C., 1963 (Box 27)
    - Speeches, remarks for Secretary of State Dean Rusk at Women's National Press Club, 1968 (Box 27)
    - Special studies, 1961-1964 (Box 27)
    - The Strategy of Peace, excerpts, 1961-1963 (Box 27)
    - Study group (Box 27)
      - Intelligence (Council on Foreign Relations), 1967-1968, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - Middle Eastern center, 1967-1969 (Box 27)
      - South Asia (Council on Foreign Relations), 1966-1967 (Box 28)
      - Speier, Hans, on Germany, 1964-1968 See also Container CL 2, same heading, (3 folders) (Box 28)
    - Travel (Box 28)
      - Africa, 1966 (Box 28)
      - Argentina, Uruguay, Chile, Venezuela, 1964-1965 (Box 28)
      - Argentina and Venezuela, 1965 (Box 28)
      - Brussels, Belgium, and Paris, France, 1962 See also Container CL 2, same heading (Box 28)
      - Canada, 1965-1966, (2 folders) (Box 28)
      - Caribbean, 1963 (Box 28)
      - Colombia, 1964 (Box 28)
      - Columbia University (conference), 1962 (Box 28)
      - Florida, Mexico, Panama, Puerto Rico, 1962 (Box 29)
      - Germany, 1962, (5 folders) (Box 29)
      - Germany, debriefing, 1962, 1967, 1999 (Box 29)
      - Germany and England, with John F. Kennedy, 1963, (2 folders) (Box 29)
      - Germany and London, England, 1967 (Box 29)
      - Guatemala, Mexico, and Jamaica, 1966 (Box 29)
      - India and Pakistan (Box 29)
        - Camp David seminar, 1964 (Box 29)
        - General, 1964, 1970 See also Container CL 2, same heading, (3 folders) (Box 30)
        - Indian subcontinent debriefing, draft, 1964 (Box 30)
        - Indian subcontinent debriefings, 1964, 2009, (2 folders) (Box 30)
      - Jamaica, Haiti, and Puerto Rico, 1967 (Box 30)
      - Middle East and South Asia, 1964 (Box 30)
      - Panama, 1964 (Box 30)
      - San Francisco, Calif. (Brookings Forum), 1969 (Box 30)
      - Uruguay and Chile, 1965 (Box 31)
      - Vouchers, 1967 (Box 31)
      - Yale University, 1965 (Box 31)
    - Undersecretary's office, 1961 See also Container CL 3, same heading (Box 31)
    - United States Intelligence Board, notes, 1961-1969 See also Containers CL 3, TS 1, and SCI 1, same heading, (7 folders) (Box 31)
    - United States Intelligence Board, notes, India and Pakistan, 1962-1967 (Box 31)
    - Vietnam, 1961-1963 See also Container CL 3, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Vietnam, 1964-1970 See also Container CL 3, same heading, (4 folders) (Box 32)
    - Vietnam, INR self-critique, summary, undated (Box 32)
    - White House correspondents dinner, 1961 (Box 32)
    - Writings (Box 32)
      - American Anthropological Association, 1967-1968 (Box 32)
      - Foreign Affairs, 1969 (Box 32)
  - United States Embassy, London, England (Box 32)
    - Address book, circa 1969 (Box 32)
    - American School in London, 1967-1969 (Box 32)
    - Annenberg, Walter H., 1969-1974, 1981-1983, 1991, 2002, 2009, (2 folders) (Box 32)
    - Appointments, 1969-1970 See also Container CL 3, same heading (Box 32)
    - Appointments, 1969-1970 (Box 33)
    - Conferences, circa 1957-1976, (4 folders) (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1970 See also Container CL 3, same heading, (3 folders) (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1970, (3 folders) (Box 34)
    - Expenses, 1969-1970 (Box 34)
    - General, 1963-1970, (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - Guest lists, 1969-1970 (Box 34)
    - Mayflower 70 celebrations, 1970 (Box 34)
    - Notes, 1969-1971 (Box 35)
    - Organizational structure, 1970-1973 (Box 35)
    - Personnel actions, 1969-1970 (Box 35)
    - Printed matter, 1964-1972, (2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Rhodesia, 1969-1970 (Box 35)
    - Southeast Asia, 1969-1970 See also Container CL 3, same heading (Box 35)
    - Southeast Asia, 1969-1970 See also Container CL 3, same heading (Box 36)
    - Speeches, 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 36)
    - Woodward Foundation, 1970 (Box 36)
- Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1948-2008 (Box 36-94)
  The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace series spans the years 1948-2008, with the bulk of the material reflecting Hughes’s tenure as the organization’s president between 1971-1991. This series primarily contains records of major projects, events, and functions the endowment undertook under Hughes's tutelage. Major topics include the Arms Control Association, Future of Arms Control panel, Face-to-Face communication program events, the Mid-Atlantic Club, Board of Trustees meetings, and publication of Foreign Policy magazine. The bulk of the series is formed by a subject file containing Hughes’s files regarding staff, projects, contractors, and organizations with which the endowment regularly collaborated. Many files contain Hughes’s notes and correspondence with individuals regarding project ideas, statuses, and outcomes. Conferences and meetings on the topics of foreign policy, nuclear arms, and United States-Soviet relations, either sponsored by the endowment or attended by Hughes, also feature prominently in the subject file and throughout the series. Also of particular note are the files documenting the Board of Trustees meetings. These files include planning materials for the endowment’s biannual board meetings, meeting minutes, reports of the president, and documents reflecting an extensive program review in 1987. Also included are letters sent to the board regarding Alger Hiss’s position as president of the organization in the wake of his accusation of espionage in 1948.
  Material types include correspondence, notes, reports, and printed matter.
  - Arms Control Association, 1960-1973, (7 folders) (Box 36)
  - Arms Control Association, 1974-1976, (7 folders) (Box 37)
  - Arms Control Association, 1977-1979, (7 folders) (Box 38)
  - Arms Control Association, 1980-1982, (7 folders) (Box 39)
  - Arms Control Association, 1982-1984, (7 folders) (Box 40)
  - Arms Control Association, 1984-1986, (7 folders) (Box 41)
  - Arms Control Association, 1987-2008, (9 folders) (Box 42)
  - Board of Trustees (Box 43)
    - Calendars, 1971, 1989-1999 (Box 43)
    - Chairmen, 1976-1989 (Box 43)
    - Corporate and social responsibility, 1971-1979 (Box 43)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1979, (6 folders) (Box 43)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box 44)
    - Finance Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 44)
    - Hiss, Alger, leave of absence, 1948-1949, 2007 (Box 44)
    - Interviews with trustees, notes, 1970 (Box 44)
    - Meetings (Box 44)
      - 1949-1979, (13 folders) (Box 44)
      - 1979-1980, (10 folders) (Box 45)
      - 1981-1982, (10 folders) (Box 46)
      - 1982-1983, (9 folders) (Box 47)
      - 1984-1986, (11 folders) (Box 48)
      - 1986-1987, (7 folders) (Box 49)
      - 1987-1989, 1988-1989; (8 folders) (Box 50)
      - 1989-1991, (7 folders) (Box 51)
      - 1991-2010, (7 folders) (Box 52)
    - Nominating Committee, 1970-1974, (2 folders) (Box 52)
    - Nominating Committee, 1975-1987, 1993, (3 folders) (Box 53)
    - Notes, 1981-1986 (Box 53)
    - Rosters, 1973-1992 (Box 53)
    - Search committee, 1989-1991 (Box 53)
  - Calendars, 1972-1979, (5 folders) (Box 53)
  - Calendars, 1980-1989, (10 folders) (Box 54)
  - Calendars, 1990-1992, (4 folders) (Box 55)
  - Executive committee, 1968-1977, (8 folders) (Box 55)
  - Executive committee, 1977-1997, (10 folders) (Box 56)
  - Face-to-Face program, 1971-1972, (2 folders) (Box 56)
  - Face-to-Face program, 1973-1982, (11 folders) (Box 57)
  - Face-to-Face program, 1982-1988, (10 folders) (Box 58)
  - Face-to-Face program, 1989-1998, (9 folders) (Box 59)
  - Foreign Policy (magazine), 1971-1974, (4 folders) (Box 59)
  - Foreign Policy (magazine), 1974-1978, (10 folders) (Box 60)
  - Foreign Policy (magazine), 1979-1983, (9 folders) (Box 61)
  - Foreign Policy (magazine), 1984-2004, (10 folders) (Box 62)
  - Future of Arms Control panel, 1979 (Box 62)
  - Future of Arms Control panel, 1980-1981, (9 folders) (Box 63)
  - Future of Arms Control panel, 1981-1983, (9 folders) (Box 64)
  - Future of Arms Control panel, 1983 (Box 65)
  - Mid-Atlantic Club, 1974-1981, (12 folders) (Box 65)
  - Mid-Atlantic Club, 1982-1986, (14 folders) (Box 66)
  - Mid-Atlantic Club, 1986-1989, (10 folders) (Box 67)
  - Mid-Atlantic Club, 1989-1998, (10 folders) (Box 68)
  - Monthly reports, 1979 (Box 68)
  - Monthly reports, 1980-1984, (5 folders) (Box 69)
  - Subject file (Box 69)
    - 21st Century, Sir John Thomson, 1988-1989 (Box 69)
    - Abramowitz, Morton, 1990-1992 (Box 69)
    - Affirmative action, 1975 (Box 69)
    - Africa - Projects, 1973-1979, 1991 (Box 69)
    - African American Institute, 1971-1972 (Box 69)
    - American Council for Jean Monnet Studies, Inc., 1990-1992 (Box 70)
    - American Foreign Service Association, 1973 (Box 70)
    - American Society of International Law, 1979-1985 (Box 70)
    - Andrew Carnegie's Peace Endowment, Larry L. Fabian, 1985 (Box 70)
    - Arnold, David (papers), 1971 (Box 70)
    - The Asia Society, 1973-1981, (4 folders) (Box 70)
    - Atlantic Institute of International Affairs, 1981-1986 (Box 71)
    - BDM Corp., Vietnam study, 1978-1979 (Box 71)
    - Boettcher, Bob, 1979 (Box 71)
    - Bolté, Charles G., 1971-1973 (Box 71)
    - Borowiec, Andrew, 1975-1977 (Box 71)
    - Breslin, Pat, 1974-1980 (Box 71)
    - Burma, Myanmar, Roger Hilsman, 1994-1997 (Box 71)
    - Carnegie centennial, 2001, 2011 (Box 71)
    - Carnegie Dunfermline Trust, circa 1984 (Box 71)
    - Carnegie European Center, Geneva Switzerland, John Goormaghtigh, 1971-1978, (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - Carnegie German Study Group, 1993 (Box 72)
    - Carnegie Moscow Center, Moscow, Russia, 1992-1996 (Box 72)
    - Casalla, Alexander, 1976-1979 (Box 72)
    - Center for a Voluntary Society, 1972-1975 (Box 72)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, National War College, Washington, D.C., 1972-1975 (Box 72)
    - Chief's Luncheon Group, 1971-1975 (Box 72)
    - Collaborations, 1982-1987 (Box 72)
    - Commission on the Middle East, 1969-1972, (3 folders) (Box 72)
    - Commission on the Middle East, 1972-1977, (5 folders) (Box 73)
    - Commission on the Organization of the Government for the Conduct of Foreign Policy, 1973 (Box 73)
    - Commission on voluntary action and third world development, 1977 (Box 73)
    - Committee on the Present Danger, 1978-1979, (2 folders) (Box 73)
    - Conferences (Box 74)
      - American Assembly, Harriman, N.Y., 1991, (2 folders) (Box 74)
      - Andrew Carnegie Sesquicentennial Gathering, Dunfermline, Scotland, 1985 (Box 74)
      - Bellagio, Italy, conference, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 74)
      - Bilderberg meetings, 1971-1985 (Box 74)
      - Bilderberg meetings, 1971-1985 (Box 75)
      - "European Security, SALT, and U.S.-European Relations," Geneva, Switzerland, 1972 (Box 75)
      - Institute for East-West Security, Potsdam, Germany, 1988 (Box 75)
      - Middle East Institute, Rosslyn, Va., 1992 (Box 75)
      - Pugwash conferences, 1976-1986, (2 folders) (Box 75)
      - Trilateral conference, New Delhi, India, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 75)
      - "U.S.-Caribbean Relations," Bridgetown, Barbados, 1977-1982 (Box 76)
      - West-West Agenda meetings, 1991-1998 (Box 76)
      - Wilton Park Conference, Steyning, England, 1991 (Box 76)
    - Conservation Foundation, Marvin Durning, 1973 (Box 76)
    - Consortium on Peace, Research, Education, and Development, 1970-1973 (Box 76)
    - Conventional Arms Proliferation, Fred Wyle, 1973-1974 (Box 76)
    - Council on Religion and International Affairs, 1971-1986, (4 folders) (Box 76)
    - Council on Religion and International Affairs, 1971-1986 (Box 77)
    - Cuba (Box 77)
      - Communications, 1977-1979 (Box 77)
      - Trip with Alamar Associates, 1977, (2 folders) (Box 77)
      - United States-Cuba Study Group, 1983 (Box 77)
    - Daedalus Project, 1978 (Box 77)
    - Deibel, Terry L., 1977-1978 (Box 77)
    - Democratic National Committee, 1972-1975 (Box 77)
    - Douglas, John, 1978-1983, (3 folders) (Box 77)
    - Douglas, John, 1984-1986 (Box 78)
    - Economic projects, 1974 (Box 78)
    - Estrangement: America and the World (book), Sanford J. Ungar, 1985 (Box 78)
    - Fabian, Larry L., 1989-1994 (Box 78)
    - Focus (television and radio program), David Biltchik, 1975-1977, (4 folders) (Box 78)
    - Foreign intelligence, 1973-1974 (Box 78)
    - Fredericks, Wayne, 1972 (Box 78)
    - Gall, Norman, 1975-1977 (Box 78)
    - Gilmore, Richard, 1974-1979 (Box 79)
    - Goodwin, Craufurd D., 2008 (Box 79)
    - Hanson, Christopher, 1974-1976 (Box 79)
    - Harris, Lee B., 1971-1972 (Box 79)
    - Hague Academy, Carnegie lecturer, 1975-1979 (Box 79)
    - Haughton, Ronald, 1971-1972 (Box 79)
    - Human rights, Warren Weinstein, 1974-1977 (Box 79)
    - Humanitarian Policy Studies Program (Box 79)
      - Biafra report, 1973-1974 (Box 79)
      - Carpenter, Margaret, Kurdish project, 1976-1978 (Box 79)
      - "Disaster in the Desert," West Africa report, 1974, (2 folders) (Box 79)
      - General, 1973-1975 (Box 79)
      - Morris, Roger, 1972 (Box 79)
      - Morris, Roger, 1973-1980, 1996, (5 folders) (Box 80)
      - "Passing By," Burundi report, 1972-1973 (Box 80)
      - "The Tar Baby Option," Rhodesia report, 1972-1976 (Box 80)
      - "Through the Looking Glass in Chile," Morris article, 1974-1975 (Box 80)
    - Incorporation, 1972-1973 (Box 81)
    - India, 1973, 1982 (Box 81)
    - India, Pakistan, 1982, 1993-1996, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - Indian subcontinent, 1971-1972 (Box 81)
    - Indochina Working Group, 1970-1973 (Box 81)
    - Institute for Congress, Alton Fyre, 1974 (Box 81)
    - Intelligence Study Group, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 81)
    - International Conciliation (magazine), 1966-1972 (Box 81)
    - International Conflict and American Organizations, Project Steering Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 82)
    - International Crisis Group, 1994 (Box 82)
    - International Law Program, Tom Franck, 1971-1979 (Box 82)
    - International Fact-finding Center, 1973-1976 (Box 82)
    - International Organization Affairs, C. William Maynes, 1972-1976 (Box 82)
    - International Organization, transnational policy, 1971-1973 (Box 82)
    - International Technical Assistance Group, 1972-1973 (Box 82)
    - Interviews, 1970 (Box 82)
    - Iraq, William R. Polk, 1997-2008 (Box 82)
    - Joffe, Josef, "U.S. Nuclear Arms: Backbone of NATO," article comments, 1983 (Box 82)
    - Johnson, Joseph, E., 1961-1972 (Box 83)
    - Joint Discussion Group on Congress and Foreign Policy, 1978 (Box 83)
    - Joint Discussion Group on Executive-Congressional Relations and Foreign Policy, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 83)
    - Katz, Milton, 1970-1977 (Box 83)
    - Labor unions, 1975-1976 (Box 83)
    - Latin America, 1975-1984 (Box 83)
    - Lewis, William, 1979 (Box 83)
    - Manglapus, Raul S., 1975-1976 (Box 83)
    - Media, 1980-1985 (Box 83)
    - Menges, Constantine Christopher, 1977-1978 (Box 83)
    - Micronesia project, Don McHenry, 1970-1974 (Box 83)
    - Morehouse, Ward, 1970-1971 (Box 83)
    - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations, 1975-1979 (Box 83)
    - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations, 1975-1992, (2 folders) (Box 84)
    - National Endowment for the Arts, Bicentennial Fellowship Exchange, 1975-1978, (3 folders) (Box 84)
    - National Security Education Act, 1992 (Box 84)
    - The Nixon Center for Peace and Freedom, 1992-2003 (Box 84)
    - Norwegian Parliament delegation, 1983 (Box 84)
    - "The Nuclear Dilemma," Episcopal Church report, 1985 (Box 84)
    - Offices (Box 84)
      - New York, N.Y., 1971-1978, (2 folders) (Box 84)
      - Washington, D.C., 1973-1974, 1988, (5 folders) (Box 85)
    - Outer Space Communication and International Organization, 1969-1971 (Box 85)
    - Outreach, 1981-1986 (Box 85)
    - Overseas Development Council, 1971-1986 (Box 85)
    - Panama, 1975-1977 (Box 85)
    - Pastoral letter, war and peace, 1982 (Box 85)
    - Pierre, Andrew, 1995 (Box 86)
    - Presidential search and dinner for Hughes, 1969-1971 (Box 86)
    - Press releases, 1972, 1988-1997 (Box 86)
    - Projects and functions, 1960-1971, 1981-1982 (Box 86)
    - Public Agenda Foundation, South Africa project, 1976-1977 (Box 86)
    - Publications policy (Foreign Policy magazine), 1974-1977 (Box 86)
    - Puerto Rico (Box 86)
      - Acevedo, Héctor Luis (Face-to-Face meeting), 1995 (Box 86)
      - Alegria, Ricardo, black conquistador, 1988-1998 (Box 86)
      - Carrión, Arturo, memorial, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Castro Gómez, Victor R., 1988 (Box 87)
      - Collado Schwarz, Ángel, 1994, 2007 (Box 87)
      - Colón, Rafel Hernández, 1973-1989 (Box 87)
      - Conference, "Puerto Rico and the Foreign Policy Process," 1973 (Box 87)
      - Culebra island, 1972-1975 (Box 87)
      - Economic zones, 1977-1978 (Box 87)
      - Face-to-Face, Future of U.S.-Puerto Rico Relationship, 1977, (2 folders) (Box 87)
      - Fundación Luis Muñoz Marín, 1962,1985-1990 (Box 87)
      - General, 1969-1994, (8 folders) (Box 88)
      - General, 2003-2011, undated, (2 folders) (Box 89)
      - Moscoso, Teodoro, 1981-1992 (Box 89)
      - Publications, 1975 (Box 89)
      - "Will Puerto Rico become a State?" Alex W. Maldonado, 1983 (Box 89)
    - Reports, miscellaneous, 1968-1987 (Box 89)
    - Roundtable discussions, meetings, luncheons, 1972-1973, 1990-1997 (Box 89)
    - Russia (photocopied documents), 1913-1917 (Box 89)
    - Schaetzel, J. Robert, and Harry Boardman, 1972 (Box 89)
    - Seven Springs Farm Center, Mount Kisco, N.Y., Joseph Greene, 1974 (Box 89)
    - Shriver, Sargent, 1972-1975 (Box 89)
    - Staden, Berndt von, dinner for, 1983 (Box 89)
    - Staff activities, 1970-1974 (Box 90)
    - Staff and projects (publications), 1974-1997 (Box 90)
    - Staff recruitment, 1971-1984 (Box 90)
    - Student Advisory Committee on International Affairs, Project Dialogue, 1971-1974, (4 folders) (Box 90)
    - Student Advisory Committee on International Affairs, Project Dialogue, 1971-1974 (Box 91)
    - Study Group on Indo-American Relations, 1981-1982, 1990-1991, (2 folders) (Box 91)
    - Study Group on U.S.-Indian Relations, 1992-1993, (3 folders) (Box 91)
    - Sturua, Melor, 1989 (Box 91)
    - Travel and Maintenance Assistance Program, 1971-1973 (Box 91)
    - Trips (Box 92)
      - Belgium, NATO visit, 1980 (Box 92)
      - China, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 92)
      - Edinburgh, Scotland, 1977 (Box 92)
      - India, 1974 (Box 92)
      - New Delhi, India, 1972 (Box 92)
    - United Fund Campaign, 1974 (Box 92)
    - United Nations, 1971-1988 (Box 92)
    - United Nations Fellowship Program, Fellows in Diplomacy, 1971-1975, (2 folders) (Box 92)
    - United Nations Study Group, 1971-1974 (Box 93)
    - United States-China relations, Victor Li, 1976-1977 (Box 93)
    - United States-Soviet Study Group, Dimitri Simes, 1979-1991, (4 folders) (Box 93)
    - United States-Soviet Relations project, Seyom Brown, 1976-1977 (Box 93)
    - United States United Nations Host Country Advisory Committee, 1967-1973 (Box 93)
    - Visiting Research Scholarship, 1971-1972 (Box 93)
    - Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs, 1971-1977 (Box 93)
    - Webster, David, 1989-1990 (Box 93)
    - Weiss, Seymour, 1992-1994 (Box 93)
    - West-West Bureau, 1984-1986 (Box 94)
    - Women's Foreign Policy Group, 1994-1996 (Box 94)
    - World of Personnel Survey, 1972 (Box 94)
    - World Peace Foundation, 1971-1983 (Box 94)
    - Zimbabwe-Rhodesia meeting, Washington, D.C., 1979 (Box 94)
    - Zwick, Charles J. (trustees), 1977-1991 (Box 94)
- General Correspondence, 1943-2006 (Box 94-127)
  The General Correspondence series was maintained as received and is arranged into three groupings: Alphabetical file, Chronological file, and Special signatures. The series primarily documents Hughes’s professional career in the Department of State and Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, with the majority reflecting Hughes’s years at the Carnegie Endowment and his contacts with diplomats and dignitaries. Topics across the series largely relate to business matters and include interoffice memos and routine outgoing correspondence. Files regarding named correspondents in the Alphabetical and Special signatures groupings often include contextual and analytical notes supplied by Hughes and, at times, associated clippings, printed matter, and other ephemera. Researchers should note that extensive personal correspondence chronicling Hughes’s undergraduate and graduate education and extracurricular activities is located in the Personal File.